[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard
knowledge is power
[Music]
let's get loose you got to do yellow
welcome to the junkyard love podcasts
this one's a little bit different this
is uh this is gonna be a solo episode
with your host me Jacob Ryan's today I
wanted to I had a podcast scheduled but
we had to reschedule last minute so I
was I was sitting there with my notes
this morning I was kind of taking some
notes of stuff I was listening to and I
was like you know I should do a general
self-care episode just what have you
learned you've been doing things on your
own for a long time now Jake what have
you learned from doing such things on
your own what has not worked what has
worked how does it work how does it
affect your life I've done a lot of I've
done a lot of different things trying
different things checking them out
seeing how they work for me seeing how
they make me feel exploring them
completely just remaining in disbelief
and allowing it to to just take me to
what what feels right to what feels good
to where I feel most like me most
centered you know and to come become
familiar with what that means you know
what's our what's our homeostasis what
what is the what is the place within
each of us that we can say like okay I
feel so comfortable relaxed I feel like
me
I feel sane I feel like I'm articulating
my words correctly my body's not
bothering me I'm not distracted by
thoughts of the future I'm not pulled
back from thoughts of the past anxiety
depression right and how did I get there
in what what is it you know what's that
what's that Center that Center just okay
it feels like I'm on the right path it
feels like this crazy life thing I think
that I'm doing okay
how do we get there what's that feeling
if you listen to this you might have
anxiety you might have depression you
might have self-loathing you might have
guilt you might have shame you might
have addiction you might have anything
guess what it's cuz you're human
we all got stuff like that everybody's
got their [__] goin on some people are
really addicted to coffee and some
people are really addicted to heroin
it's just what happens but you can
change you can improve your life you can
learn more insert new knowledge into
your dome up here and become a better
version of yourself you can change the
identity that held those things that did
those things that were not beneficial to
you
you could really explore I've spent the
last few years a couple years just a
hundred percent in self development mode
just learning about myself and learning
about the reality around me and learning
about other people and learning how I
perceive things differently than other
people and learning how I can be the
master of my emotions and learning how I
can just see things from a different
lens and change and really develop I
mean I hardly recognize who I was a
couple years ago a completely different
person I don't respond the same way my
emotions aren't the same my my
homeostasis is not nearly the same I
wake up in the mornings in a they're way
better than they used to be used to just
wake up in the mornings and I wasn't
pumped to be alive but now I am I'm
excited partly because I think we got a
puppy a few months ago and he just
sleeps next to me so I wake up and I see
a puppy right away so that's the first
tip is get a puppy he's a pain in the
butt but you can't you can't just be mad
Mia wake up and see a puppy just smiling
at you ready to be pet so let's uh let's
see so I wrote a bunch of notes here and
this episode isn't gonna be entirely
structured I think that I crippled
myself a little bit when I try to
structure things too much and I try to
plan them or I try to you know I'll end
up writing like five pages of notes and
then still thinking that I didn't really
get the whole thing
and then I'm just wore out from doing
that and then I lose my oven don't
record the video so I've got a couple
pages of notes one and a half to be
exact ish and I just wrote a bunch of
bullet points that I'm gonna scroll
through I did separate things into how
to take care of yourself physically and
mentally there was texting my friend
Spencer and we were we were discussing
the importance of mentioning our
relationship with others as well our how
much and how easily does someone cause
you to lose control of your own emotions
how is one small interaction one small
thing someone says enough to you know
push you away from the control of your
own emotions push you into a thought
right into a thought about the thing
that they said and then sure enough it's
been an hour and that thought became
just a feeling and then you're the one
who had to feel it there they typed
something online they said something in
an interview they saw something on TV or
the news that you didn't like and it
caused you to have a bad time at home so
a lot of times other people's opinions
or other people's way of wording things
are enough to like trigger something
within us and if we don't have the
ability the power the the mind
sharpening the the skill of noticing
right of the awareness that it happened
and that emotion can send you flying for
hours and it's happened everybody it
happens to me all the time
you know I get better and better as I go
along the more I meditate the more I
learn about the nature of my own mind
the more I'm able to realize when I'm
caught up in an emotion when I'm caught
up in like getting angry about something
somebody said and I'm not really
logically thinking of how it's affecting
me here and okay well I mean it's cool
to have an opinion on that but is it
catapulting my whole mood right now is
it catapulted my whole life do I have
other work to do is it important for me
to be mad about this thing right now
because I've got important work to do
instead of that so you've got a there's
so many different ways to take care of
your mind and that's all of these things
whether we're talking about the mental
health
physical health your relationship with
others they all they all pass through
your mind don't they they're all seen
through they're all experienced through
the consciousness they're all perceived
through our five senses we you know we
see things we hear that we smell it we
taste it and then through in touch it in
through a combination of these five
senses we form who we are in our
opinions in our our reactions to things
and then thus for we we kind of
formulate a personality out of that and
I think there's a lot of us you know
especially depending on your age and
your upbringing and what you studied and
what you know and and what your beliefs
are prior you know if you're anything
like me you've never really taken a look
at your belief so you never really took
a look at your values you never asked
yourself he had values you never really
sat down and asked why you are the way
that you are and for me when I when I
started doing that um I started
realizing a lot of the person I was
walking around a lot of the person who
was like feeling this pain and this
anxiety in this depression and thinking
I'm thinking I'm this and and having bad
thoughts and I thought that I had kind
of become that person I had kind of my
habits had lined up and made me into the
things that I am my my you know my
childhood my teenage years the person
that I had to be for those monumental
times in my life to survive and navigate
the world around me that person wasn't
wasn't that part of me didn't fit into
my life now I had grown out of the
person who had helped me who had who I
had become from a young age the person
who protected me in the person who who
made me me and allowed me to survive and
allowed me to adapt and allowed me to
realize what I needed to do I was that
person but I got caught up in being that
person and you get to different times in
your life
where
you got to be able to look at if it's
working out for you or not there's this
scene and get him to the Greek with
Russell Brand and Jonah Hill where
towards the end he jumps off this
Russell Brandt jumps off this he's
partying jumps off a roof
pardon me for fiddling with my pants
here he jumps off a roof essentially and
he jumps into a pool a pool of water
well on the way down he Clips his arm on
the edge of the on the edge of the the
pool there and it's just like snaps it
and there's blood and it's just like
hectic and it's it's this ridiculous
scene but I just remember he has this
part where where he's like Aaron well
I'm doing is just not working out for me
anymore like he's just he's just laying
there in the pool he just he got drunk
and in whatever party jumped off the
roof and he's trying to be the cool guy
the egotistical like look at me look at
me and it jumps off and he's the one who
suffers like people might be cheering
cool but then they're moving on with
their life they're like how cool all
right anyway on to the next one like
who's gonna make a fool of himself now
he's he's the one who was experiencing
it in this movie you bust his arm and he
says Aaron it's not working out for me
and I think that you know maybe that's
kind of where I got is I just realized
through circumstance through finally not
making myself just the victim of all
these things like ah it's crazy how much
bad stuff happens to me like momma Bob
but I wasn't doing anything to help it
or aid it I think that I just realized
that it wasn't working out for me right
the way that I was doing things was not
working out it worked great for my
sixteen-year-old self the person that I
had to build the person who had to
survive my childhood years who I built
to be a savage to be a tough kid to be
independent and happy and inspirational
and funny like the person that I built
at the age of 15 16 was perfect for that
time in my life but ask yourself if
you're at a time in your life where the
person that you've built doesn't seem to
be fitting very well with that puzzle
piece you know is it is it time to
change is it time to take a look at what
am i doing what have
I've been doing that isn't getting me to
where I want to go because we get so
caught up with looking at our our life
right now looking at you know it's it's
our instant gratification mindset has
really changed our perception of our
everyday reality especially if you're
someone who is enveloped in social media
and news and in just a technology a lot
of a lot of input right the input
changes our everyday actions it kind of
if you're not aware of how things affect
you from the external world how the
information how the things you're
consuming affect your everyday thought
patterns you've got to take a second
look at it you've got it you've got to
say okay what am I thinking about and
why am I thinking it who am i arguing
with and why am i why am i arguing with
them you know there's I think that if
you let's put it this way one day you're
gonna die one day listener you're gonna
die just like I'm gonna die I'm gonna
pass away I'm gonna leave this earth and
who knows what comes next
but the way that I see it now is I ask
myself what do I want to what do I want
to have had experienced and I think you
could also ask yourself what did I spend
my time caring about alright imagine
being on your deathbed and this doesn't
have to be a solemn a solemn thing this
is not a sad thing life is made
beautiful because of death life is made
beautiful because it doesn't last
forever right wonder is not knowing so I
think if you ask yourself what what if I
spent my time caring about if you kind
of envision yourself use your user
imagination here and just think of
yourself like look at your body and like
man what am I getting in in 60 years in
70 years whatever how long it is when
I'm I'm like okay well since that time
my body is is biologically ready to roll
you know let's let's do this like are
you gonna are you gonna be proud that
you that you argued with all those
people on face
are you gonna be are you gonna be proud
that you spent hours and hours getting
the right Instagram photo are you gonna
be proud that you were not present at so
many different places because you were
on your phone caring about the wrong
things I think that we just don't take a
look at what we're doing we're just
we're caught up and enjoying it right
we're caught up we're caught up in the
act of doing and it's distracting us
from the act of living you know so I
guess the advice that I'm giving in this
video I'm gonna get going here is it's
just I hope that everybody takes a look
at where they're at in their life I'm
not trying to tell anybody that they're
wrong I'm not trying to tell anybody
that I'm better than them certainly not
that I'm not trying to to say these are
the only ways I'm not trying to I'm not
trying to point out where you're bad and
point out what will make you better as
if that's you know my opinion matters or
I'm following some you know I'm no
religious leader I'm no like pastor
standing up here and saying you're gonna
get into heaven or you're gonna get
these things if you do these things I'm
just just trying to say here's what's
helped me you know here's here's what I
found out and here's my understanding of
it and you know I I have my dark days I
do and I have human emotions you know
hey you know how bad days and I
procrastinate and sometimes I don't eat
that grade and and sometimes I'll have
you know one too many beers and when I'm
like uh-huh I think this is the last one
oh [__] it I'll do another one
you know there's so many I'm human right
but you're human too
so as you're listening to these things
if they point out if they trigger you if
they point out things in you that you
don't like if you don't agree with them
just just I just asked you stop and say
what why why does this trigger me why
does this make me annoyed why do I think
something about the person saying it
rather than perceiving it through my
life you know when I watch movies when
I'm interacting with a movie or a TV
show the way that I personally just
because the my personality type my
perception of reality right is is I live
through them I say Oh what if what in my
life is incredibly similar to this and
how could I draw the emotion from that
and how can I draw the essence of this
scene from this movie by inserting it
into me you know it's not me watching
the movie and I'm judging these people
and I'm wondering what they're doing I'm
I'm in the movie I'm I'm really thinking
about I'm just trying to imagine Oh what
if I was experiencing that what what if
I had something very similar to that and
it makes me feel the emotions much more
intently I think in in it's just a way
of perceiving things in a way of making
your mind learn from everything that
you're consuming a lot of that were
consuming we're just reacting to we're
just starting with the state of reaction
in in in instead of trying to perceive
it and saying okay like these people did
those things and I'm you know if you're
watching a movie about Hitler and you're
sitting there just I hate him and he's
such a piece of blah and blah blah but
then like he teaches you the most
incredible technique to play the
saxophone that you've ever seen in your
entire life I mean you were busy judging
him and that's probably the worst
example I could ever think of off the
top of my head using Hitler let's back
up there but I think that when we spend
so much time projecting who we think we
are onto the things that we're consuming
whether it's movies or social media or
any of these things news even our
day-to-day interactions we we miss the
opportunity to we miss the good in it
you know we were always trying to say
well I'm this and we're trying to assess
who we are in comparison to what we're
consuming right but there's so much more
beauty and so much more to learn when
you're perceiving things in a different
way when you're perceiving things
through how could I do that
how am i doing that how can I get to the
conceptualization of understanding that
thing that they're Express
to me so a good a good place to start is
let's say mornings
what's your morning's like do you wake
up in a reactive state and what I mean
by that is do you wake up and check your
cell phone think about it you're
dreaming about whatever the heck you're
dreaming about and you wake up and you
forget it within I mean 80 seconds max
you forgot everything I think it's like
20 seconds you forget you forget the
first 20% and then you're like right
after you forget it so you're freeing
the dream and then think about you know
as your senses are coming awake you're
feeling your body you're moving in
stretch and give them that morning yawn
and you lean over and you're checking
the time the first thing of course
that's that's why you check your phone
is because you got to check the time but
that's what's kind of what we tell
ourselves because if there's emails if
there's texts we really want to check
those too right well it's not great to
start your day off in a react Airy state
think about if you got some Apple news
spotlight and they're Sayed Trump tweets
that alt all people on the left are lip
tardes and he hates them Murr and then
your your your someone on the left and
so now your identity has just been
activated within the first 20 seconds of
your day and you're like dude I'm pissed
this guy sucks
bah-bah-bah and then you're you're
fighting an argument in your head
against somebody who's not actually
there in front of you not in physical
reality you are mad because you've
almost just been given like a text or
word curse right like they they can the
magic words were shown to you from your
your magic box this phone thing here
within a few seconds of waking up and
you were reactive a lot of times the the
first thing when we do when we wake up
and we check even if there's not any bad
things to react to we get on social
media and we scroll and we see what
everybody's up to how was everybody's
night how's everybody's morning what's
everybody doing and it's I mean you can
learn a lot about dopamine and how like
the light affects us two of our phones I
don't want to make this video too much
about like the science behind stuff
because I think I'll prize [__] that up
and tell you like the wrongs do
tist --ax I've learned it I don't
remember the exact you know numbers and
such but I've applied these things I've
taken a look at them and see how they
work for my own life so what I do is I
wake up and I try not to check my phone
right away especially if I know that I
need to get to do in something if I know
I want to get up and meditate right if I
know I want to get the momentum that I
need to get so I wake up and I control
what I consume what I'm consuming I like
to not check my email and stuff I don't
you know if you can keep your phone on
Do Not Disturb even our airplane mode
and then not turn it off until you've
been up for 30 minutes so self-care
first thing you do in the morning wake
up and what are your thoughts just
observe your thoughts as soon as your
feet touch the ground are you internally
complaining about um you know oh I
didn't sleep very good or oh my neck
hurts or are you doing like a typical
complaint to the person next to you if
you have a significant other or or what
are you talking about are you setting
yourself up are you are you realizing
that you just woke up to this day and
say what do I want out of today because
because if not we just wake up and we're
just a ball of habits right we just wake
up and we do what the phone does and
then whatever the phone leads us to say
afterwards or whatever mood were in and
then we just kind of zombie through you
know go downstairs make your coffee and
in eat your breakfast and blah blah I
think really stopping yourself and
putting a putting a pin in in in your
morning and say what do I want out of
this day so be aware in the morning
don't let your phone throw you for a
dang loop and don't let your phone
control you don't let other people on
the other side of the world control your
physical reality right now don't let
them activate your biological meet
vehicle here you know like your your
your what's an amygdala the back part
the reptilian part of our brain that
keeps us alive the the fight and flight
the the fear it gets activated by a text
you can get you can get triggered listen
to this you can feel the effects of
bungee-jumping from your thoughts in
your bed so you're laying in bed heart
rate monitor on you and then there's a
dude say the exact same time the other
the world in there doing a livestream of
it the dude jumps off or he's about to
jump off bungee but jumping and his
heart rates going through the roof his
physiology is mu and they're measuring
you laying in bed being stressed out
having anxiety attack or being mad or
being angry and learning or responding
Anna you can with your brain make your
body feel the equivalent of if you're
about to bungee jump do you think that's
good for your body do you think that's
healthy because it's not notice when
things are affecting you because of your
phone notice when your emotions are
going through a loop because of your
phone because of this thing especially
in the morning please take care of your
morning so get out of bed what you need
to be doing is stretching stretching
look it we think of stretching and we
think of working out as like these
separate things in our everyday life
like did you work out today did you burn
calories did you burn more than you
output as far as calories but we don't
really look at health as like how do I
feel what does my body feel like if you
have aches and pains when you wake up if
you have creaks and whatever I mean are
you stretching are you drinking copious
amounts of water to get all the the
lubrication in between your joints are
you what are we 85% water you need to be
noticing when you're having these things
so you can so you can a fix them and
start start taking the check on them for
me I wake up and I like to do a little
bit of stretching right in the morning
it's a little bit difficult with young
with young puppers blue now but I try to
make it work you know I bend over and I
slowly and I try to stretch the micro
muscles in my neck right I try to move
my eyes around move my face around you
know things that if you're if you're
standing in public you probably feel
like a total weirdo if you were doing
you people be like what's that guy on
drugs what's he doing what's he doing
just like moving his face around and
stretching and being weird well you're
getting judge for using your own body
don't judge yourself for expressing your
own body and exploring your own body
we're not made to be so stagnant but we
are we have biologically advanced to
this point that we are now
as humans and were not prepared for the
lifestyle that we had the iPhone only
came out in 2007 friends 2007 think
about how a different our life's are and
I'm not just talking about getting on
social media in the morning at this
point I'm talking about how often we
don't move I mean imagine we're
hunter-gatherers right Paleolithic times
we are we're always chasing food we're
always on the move we're always active
when you need something you have to go
make it when you when you need to you
have to use your hands you don't just
have you're sitting here for eight hours
and then someone walks over and hands
you like a wrapped up piece of beef
jerky that's completely cured and ready
to go and you just you start eating it
times are different we've adjusted or or
we've changed but we haven't adjusted
right so you need to get in tune with
the modern times and get your body in
tune with modern times meaning you've
got to learn to stretch you've got to
learn to move your body you've got to
separate the [__] gym from physical
health and I'm someone who's always been
working out since I was a 10th grade in
high school
I started working out and I never
stopped that took no more than a week
off from from high school to the age of
like 26 I constantly would workout and I
would go to the gym but I wouldn't ever
stretch I didn't like doing cardio
because it's like this like fun joke to
just hate cardio I don't know it just
becomes part of your personality after a
while I got I don't do cardio and it's
like you practically wear a shirt that
says I don't do cardio and it kind of
just condemns you I guess but I you know
I think we do a lot of these little
things to ourselves we separate them
into unattainable separate separate
things we we think of working out as
something that's going to burn calories
because if we burn enough calories then
our body's gonna look good to other
people and when we see ourselves in the
mirror it's gonna look good and then
we'll will feel better and we'll be at
that body weight and that's good well
you're gonna keep living what about next
year and the year after that and the
year after that what if you never figure
out how to be healthy what if you never
figure out what
matter if you get to a goal weight you
know if you don't know how to maintain
that weight if you don't understand if
you don't understand how your body works
and how your body feels we're so
obsessed with weight which is a great
from here to there let's let's compare
how far how far I've gotten let's see if
I can push myself to be a little bit
better in this area wait wait in these
numbers we're so obsessed with in our
society and they tell you like you
should be this if you're a female you
should be this weight and a male you
should be this if you're this way well
again what about how you feel get good
at sharpening how you feel so wake up in
the morning and do some stretches you
don't have to do it for 20 minutes you
have to do it for 10 minutes you have to
do it for five minutes you do it for
three minutes just move around move your
eyes move your body move your fingers
and breathe breathe are you breathing
into your belly or are you breathing
from your chest are you shallow
breathing you can change your physiology
you can change where you breathe from I
used to be breathe from my chest I
worked out all the time
I would always be working out but I
never thought that I had to change my
breath I would breathe like along with
my workouts but I didn't realize where I
was breathing from I didn't realize
where I'm feeling the breath so you can
get in tune with these things you can
really start learning about your breath
start getting intimate with your breath
there's a lot of breath work online you
could look up wim HOF breathing you can
do all these anxiety breaths there's a
there's a lot of when it comes to yoga
there's a lot of breath work there but
even even the stretch outside of all
this breath work and all this you know
we see like in the holistic medicine
world we see a lot about breath work a
lot of people use breath work for
emergency situations for handling
anxiety attacks it's all wonderful but I
think that before that taking a look at
your breath and noticing at all times
just throughout the day just try to
think of a home where where's my breath
right now and if it's up in your chest
and if it's up and it's shallow and
you're in you're not really feeling your
body maybe just okay and then try to try
to mentally put your breath down in your
belly and maybe that sounds weird and
maybe that's not something you can do
right now but I assure you as someone
who was not able to do that before who
just had shallow chest breathing my
whole life
even though I was running and working
out and doing all these things and ever
take took a look at my breath
so put your breath in your belly there's
plenty of research online you can look
look up about breath work beep at Ben
pacol see the coal see I always forget
how to say his last name but uh he's
he's a wonderful dude he's like the yoga
bodybuilder he's got a couple podcasts
on breath work check those out so in the
mornings you wake up you're stretching
you're doing a little breath work it
hasn't even been four minutes in you're
already feeling better right whatever
you were thinking or imagine walking on
your phone you're you texting your
keyboard warrant on Facebook back rather
than just taking care of yourself and
taking stock of what's in front of you
so breath work stretching love your body
learn about your body and don't judge
yourself about where you're at right now
don't say oh I am good at breath work or
oh I am bad at stretching or my body
doesn't move well of course your body
doesn't know because you haven't [__]
moved it much move around and remember
that life is life is long man life is a
journey it's not just right now we
always wanted to find ourselves by right
[__] now who am i right now and where
are my muscles and how do I look right
exactly now you never get to the point
we think that we're getting somewhere
like we're gonna arrive at these places
and all right well when I look like this
and I have an 8 pack and I'm perfect and
I'm good to go
that's all I ever need to do well what
about the day after that learn about
your body smell an environment so smell
was a weird thing like I said I'll skip
around here smell is something that for
me is a big deal it's more of just sense
and it's more it's less about the smell
like there's a magic smell but in the
mornings I have my own little like like
Zen habitual things working from home
here I do like a citrus scent and for me
I've just given myself like okay when
you smell that well you get it going
it's party morning routine like I'll get
my coffee going as my coffees going I'll
walk around and I'll refill my essential
oils and it's just lemon and citrus and
I it's not because I think it's not
because I have information
on citrus being the best for focus and
it's the secret entrepreneur hack no
it's just that I've given that power and
I like the smell of citrus and so I know
all right Jake you smell on that citrus
you smell on that orange that lemon that
tangerine mmm that smells great it's
time to work it's time to focus it's
time to be lively time to be grateful
about the life around you right so I
give those things power so if you have a
scent if you have something that every
morning even if it's only for 20 minutes
as you're kind of like getting ready in
the kitchen whatever like if you have a
favorite candle scent light it and what
does that set mean and you can install
these things so when you smell them
you're like okay all right we're getting
ready for a good day you know we let
life happen to us if we don't really
prep for our day if we don't really ask
ourselves like what kind of mood do I
want to be in today you know maybe we're
just gonna be in the mood that other
people put us in what about that lights
so this goes back with screen time you
want to make sure that you know even
before bed you want to make sure that
you're not having a ton of blue light
right into your eyes I got to say I'm
pretty guilty of that myself there is on
iPhones there is a nighttime mode I'm
sure everybody knows about that
there is blue blocking glasses if you
work if you work from home or you
consume content a lot before bed you can
put on blue they believe block certain
UV rays I'm not sure exactly how it
works my friend dev got me a pair they
do work it helps you shut off certain
dopamine triggers in your brain or relax
em or slow them down I'm just a DJ here
but a light lights in the morning as
well so right along with screen time
right along with morning and night
screen time how much you're consuming is
for me I've got this thing with Philips
hue lights I love I love the Philips hue
lights I I got lucky and my friend had
like got me a bunch of them or giving me
a bunch of fun for cheap but so I have
kind of like a just every morning like
certain times in the morning where I I I
changed the color of the light I changed
the dim in the room right and I have
like my alarms go out you know like I
think it's 7:30 in the morning and I
have my lights turned to a certain thing
and it kind of tells me different times
the day and that's another thing just on
top of scent right it's not a magical
thing I'm not saying that like God comes
down he's like if you get the right hue
of blue you will unlock enlightenment no
it ain't like that it's just because I
say this is the color that that I prefer
in the morning in it also in and I have
installed that color I put in that color
and I continuously use that color every
day because I have chosen that that is
my focus that's my motivate that's my
let's get going that's my good morning
it's wonderful it's great to be alive
you know we don't think about these
things we don't really stop and take a
look at our environment but you can and
you can adjust your environment and and
you can make it work just greatly great
for you so if you don't work from home
maybe you have get one Phillips you or
or get one they have so many different
lights smart home lights where you can
set timers to where it does a certain
thing at a certain time in the morning
and it's just another reminder of how
you want to be and how you want to live
your life and how you want to set your
mood to be so set up your mood for that
[Music]
grounding crowning's good in the morning
I try to not everytime because sometimes
it's just like whoo but in the mornings
I do try to take my shoes off when I go
out to take the dog outside try to
connect to the earth there's a ton of
information on barefoot on grounding
techniques on you know look we're from
the earth right this big old giant space
rock evolution wise we're the thing that
grew after it so whether you think your
star seed whether you identify as a star
seed or not you probably are one right
so we're all just coming from this earth
and so it feels good to reconnect with
it there's so much research you can do
on that a lot of it's pretty woowoo and
a lot of it seems strange but man there
is something about going outside and
bare feet and you know weather maybe not
in the morning but if you want to go
outside bare feet and just yell that
probably gonna feel pretty damn good
you're gonna feel you're not you're not
gonna be able to explain it but you're
gonna feel lighter afterwards you're
gonna feel like you let it go there's
some connection to the earth that we
need to re-establish we're so distant
from the earth we have shoes now
we've had shoes for a while right but we
haven't on the timeline of humans I
don't think we've had this like rubber
electricity blocking situation for too
long I don't know that we know how much
it really affects you know we're
energetic beings we're we're affected by
those sort of things so get outside get
bare feet see if it works for you try
that out
in the mornings fasting um
I'll suggest fasting I've been doing it
for the last I don't know year and a
half most days the internment it fast in
my fasting I mean I don't eat after a
certain time at night so let's say after
8 or 9 I don't consume anything's just
water because if it has any calories
it'll it'll make you break your fast so
no no calories just water before bed and
then I wake up and I don't have
breakfast and everybody says breakfast
the most important meal of the day but
that was probably Kellogg's food guide
pyramid trying to sell us some [__] and
trying to lie to us so breakfast break
fast as we've discussed on the podcast
before you're breaking your fast it's
the longest time that you've gone
without food you were sleeping I grew up
thinking that my blood sugar was always
low and I'd get shaky and I'd like
mentally convinced myself that I didn't
feel good and my body felt really bad
and I didn't like being uncomfortable
and so I'd have to eat but once I
started pushing the edge like alright
try a little bit longer try a little bit
longer and just working and consuming I
would I would be like ok it's been at
like I purposely wanted to not eat but
now it's been a couple hours so they
even thought about eating I'm not even
that hungry and it's been 12 hours
already okay let's just wait two or four
more hours I'll be fine and then so the
next day you stopped eating at a certain
time and the next day you're going to
say I'm not eating until this time and
then you just stick to it
that's all that's it maybe have like an
emergency I feel like I'm gonna die and
I'm at work I have an important meeting
and I'm feeling all shaky and like a
weirdo and like I'm talking too fast
because I'm just fasting I'm not used to
it my metabolism is going crazy right
now you know have like an emergency
granola bar so you can break your fast
for sure especially if you don't work
from home but otherwise
for fasting it's as simple as set a time
I'm not gonna eat till 2 p.m. I'm not
gonna eat till 11 a.m. whatever gets you
to 14 or 16 hours you don't have to be
crazy anal about it you can do your own
research on this please do your own
research on this on fasting on what
works for you and long are fast but for
the most part just consume water and
minerals are going to be going to be
kind of important here you know you're
depleting your body with a lot of sodium
so me personally if I'm fasting for more
than like my typical 12 or 14 hours I
will add some salt water some sodium I
like pink Himalayan sea salt to my water
and just gives me the minerals and gets
me moving around and make sure my body's
not to clean up sodium so I just do wake
up in the morning and I don't have no
food the only thing that I consume is
coffee I have a couple vitamins that I
take but those are non fat soluble
vitamins and there's obviously no
calories in those and well they're not
they're not even vitamins that won't
couldn't do it but so I I wait I wait to
eat until I hit the 1416 hour mark and I
have a cup of coffee though
so I wake up and I have a cup of coffee
I don't put cream in my coffee because
if there's any calories in your coffee
just coffee by itself not flavored even
if it's a coffee pods don't put in the
flavor you don't need the flavor just
get black coffee and deal with it it's
great it starts growing on you now I
love black coffee now I don't no one on
the fruit fruit stuff I slowly started
working towards it so if you're wherever
you're at if you have creamer in a
coffee maybe slowly start working
towards I can get some nut pods get some
different kinds of cream and get some
non-dairy creamer and then maybe next
month set a day I'm like alright this is
the day I'm not gonna drink coffee and
then dude give yourself four days four
days later you're gonna forget that
you're not gonna drink creamer four days
later you're gonna forget that you that
you love the taste of coffe coffee with
Kramer like five days later a week later
just have patience with yourself realize
oh I don't get the most mouths pleasure
that I want in the morning big deal you
choosing mouth pleasure over something
that can benefit you greatly fasting I
[__] love it
cognitively it's one of the best things
it's great for inflammation
I have redness and like eczema and dry
skin and weird skin infections on my
nose and it really sub-sub dudes when
I'm fasting so there's a ton of benefits
of fasting please look it up see if it's
right for you
be careful work your way into it but
give that a try
self-care fasting check it out so diet
diet before bed it's kind of important
try not to eat within three hours of
going to bed even if you're not fasting
it's just a good rule of thumb to not
have you or not have your digestive
system trying to crank away and work
while you're while you're sleeping man
it's sometimes it doesn't always happen
and you don't have to go to bed angry if
you're like I just ate because I was
starving don't go to bed being mad at
yourself if you did eat but start to
notice okay what time is it
am I gonna die if I'm hungry is it the
end of the world to be hungry Jake is it
cuz it's not and you just kind of build
that resilience you tell yourself it's
okay I don't have to I don't have to
please my mouth right now yeah I'm gonna
go to bed in 45 minutes I'm not super
tired right now I'm trying to wind down
normally what I do is I eat a whole bag
of chips on the couch until I fall
asleep and then I get up and I go to bed
well you're choosing that over how you
feel in the morning when you start I'm
especially with fasting but if you start
not eating a bunch of shitty food or not
eating any calories within three hours
of going to bed you start waking up a
little more clear you notice how much
you are stomach you tummy affects your
cognitive abilities so food before bed
diet in general I'm gonna try to cover
this just briefly so for me a lot of it
is being honest with yourself about your
diet a lot of it for me it's like I
would eat so good four times a week and
then the other three days would just be
punishment like alright I ate my
four-times good and now it's just to
wreak havoc on this poor meat vehicle
you have here Jake wreak havoc on it eat
as many muchos Gracias burritos as you
can get all the green sauce it's your
feeding time if it's these three days I
would basically be like Friday Saturday
Sunday I'd be like let's go in I mean
I'd have maybe like one or two meals of
like you know veggies and steak and
stuff but I would otherwise I would not
even have a limo
whatever my mouth wants to consume I'm
just gonna eat all of it give me all the
candy give me all the burritos give me
all the pizza gave me the fast food and
I thought that that was good
and I thought that I don't think it was
good I thought that it was okay I knew
that I wasn't like a superstar athlete
I'm just trying to maintain living my
life trying to have some beers in a
burrito you know but these things add up
so if you like that if you have four
days on and three days of crap eating
maybe lower it down to two or maybe try
to have one cheat day these when it
comes to diet we overcomplicated so much
because we count our calories and we try
to add to our goal weight and you know
there's that weight thing again that's
why do we care about that because the
people who make money off of us buying
these programs and all this [__] they
they tell us half the information so we
so we get involved and we stay stuck on
these things it sucks learn about your
body diet wise inflammation inflammation
is one of the most common things that
causes so much [__] I think when
we're later on in civilization when we
look back and we realize what's been
killing us we're gonna look at
information as like like dude that's up
there were cigarettes like if we just
focused on not having on foods that
didn't cause us to be inflamed
I mean cigarettes sugar so sugar is not
just in sour patch kids in chocolate
bars sugar is in [__] everything
artificial sugar just because it's not
one of the five things that the FDA says
that they have to have on the package
does not mean that it's good for the
human body
don't don't trust these companies that
are telling you that it's a diet or it's
a fat-free or it's a bla bla bla don't
don't be a sucker to those things please
do you can do a little bit of research
you know like learn about these things
it seems like it always goes in a circle
right like everything in them in the
Men's Fitness or them are the muscle
magazines or whatever and not
particularly Men's Fitness I don't know
much about them but the the everything
contradicts each other like what you
read this week is not what you read next
week in in in the issue next month says
that they did a new study and everything
they learned about the the caloric
intake of these ages Baba's is wrong I
think that all that stuff that we think
we need to get into when it comes to
fitness as
just your average day every day just
[__] well it's too much we're
not and we're not huge athletes here you
know if you're just a regular person
that wants to take care of your body and
not feel like crap and not and not be
not be ashamed of the person that you
that the food you're consuming has has
made you look just don't overthink these
things you don't need to do a ton of
protein powders you don't need to do a
ton of vitamins and supplements
I do recommend some you know find what
works for you but at the beginning if
you're just like I want to get stopped
eating so crap and I just want to like
learn about my body inflammation man
just just learn about information is
this gonna give is this going to inflame
my body start there and then from there
if you don't want to count calories I I
don't I don't like counting calories I
don't think it works I don't think it
reaches towards the right goals it
doesn't really emphasize on my correct
why for me it it when it comes to food
you know if you just think of it as
mouths pleasure right if you just try to
say you don't have to like hate yourself
for everything you're eating that's for
sure you don't have to analyze
everything that you're about to put in
your mouth and say like is this good or
bad but you know there are some benefits
to that there is you know you feel
really good and you want to relieve that
that feeling of hunger so you eat but
then if you immediately feel fill
self-hatred you feel guilt or you feel
shame or you wish that you didn't eat it
maybe that's something that you
shouldn't be if within five minutes it
makes you feel look I don't like that I
don't know if that's the best thing for
you to be eating just listen to your
body it's it's obvious stuff right you
know like get your greens in there you
know yeah there's all these diets right
there's all you know there's there's
keto there's carnivore there's paleo
there's whole xxx whole xxx was one of
the things one of the diets that taught
me the most because it was just 30 days
of breaking my like sugar addictions
that I would justify and didn't realize
that I had so it helped me there but I
think that all these diets that are
drastic they get people away from the
common
foods that get people away from like
okay well whether you're on keto or
whether you're on hole 30 or whether
you're on paleo you don't eat fast food
for 30 days so you don't need fast food
for these certain Mondays you don't eat
candy bars you Tony the things wrapped
in wrapped in wrappers that are
instantly able to just pop in your mouth
all these preservatives sure the FDA
approves them but the FDA says yeah I
didn't kill you after six months marking
it everybody can have it the laws aren't
exactly looking out for us the the
things that we're allowed to consume
they say serving sizes but they know
damn well that our human biological meat
vehicles here are just were captured by
by these wonderful amazing like
delicious tasting things in this
[__] that they say to market us
these foods are not good for our body
when we're just shoving them in there so
enjoy your life enjoy food you know like
choose your battles though don't punish
yourself all the time and don't say I'm
gonna get going cuz I got that or I'm
gonna start working on my health later
when I got that when I have time when
I've got that vacation that I want to
get ready for look at your health in a
different way
change the view the person who is
viewing health the first person who is
viewing your body what does he think
what does he feel how does he feel when
he's eating these certain things how
does she feel when when she just ate all
that food and she feels self-loathing
and how does that affect other areas of
your life you know like you eat bad food
you feel bad and you think that's all
just weight related and well now the
number on the scale went but what about
the the cognitive things you just did
yourself what about the sadness that you
feel what about the shame that you feel
what about the there's a lot of things
that are attached to these to our to our
food consumption that we don't have to
feel and I know it's hard and I've I've
gone through my my weight gains and I've
gone through my constant inflammation I
feel better now than I've ever felt
because I've learned more about food
I've learned more about my body I've
learned more about other ways I've
really let myself
think in different terms and say what if
and challenge my beliefs like if you if
you've been doing something constantly
and it's not working out for you if
you've been doing the same exact
workouts for years and years even trying
the same as like diet for years and
years and you're still like in the same
place you don't feel like you've learned
that much maybe you should shift what
you're doing but just you aren't this
person forever take care of the rest of
you take care of how am I gonna feel for
the next 50 years in ten years if you
learn all the information that you need
about your body if you learn more about
the human body you don't need to
remember these certain things that these
diets sold you you need to only eat
these certain things you just learn so
learn about nutrition and how it makes
your body feel and learning is not all
statistics learning is not all facts
learning is not all it's not all finding
the right information and trying to
compare this study to this study you
know learning you as an individual have
to learn in learn how you learn right
you have to figure out what feels good
to you get in tune with that I promise
it's something that you can sharpen and
I'm if you're listening to this and
you've tried tons of diets if weight has
been a struggle for you it's not
something that you should feel ashamed
about it's not something that you should
add a layer of like saying that you suck
you're judging yourself for who you are
right now and that's not how [__] works
you've been experiencing and learning
about your body in such an advanced
crazy society here you know like we've
been sold so much [__] food in so many
addictions to different things like
think about how many people drink diet
coke that don't want to drink diet coke
think about that we drink things that we
don't want to drink we eat things that
we say we don't want to eat which one of
these people is you like oh I don't want
to eat that what then why did you it's
because our habits and our addictions in
our are our dopamine releases are our
setup their habitual they're they're
there
captured by the powers that be by the
evil corporations they're trying to make
us fat if you guys have seen wall-e
if you've seen the movie wall-e where
they just like float around in those
pods and they're like watching TV all
day and then they're just sucking on big
gulps that's what we're going for that's
what they want right but seriously just
learn don't just learn just just learn
how you feel that's learning we're going
to go with caffeine
so I mentioned coffee don't have too
much of it though that's something that
I would drink a couple monsters I used
to work in a lumber mill worked in
lumber mill for five years and Monday
through Thursday worked in a lumber mill
and then on the weekends I would be
deejaying or working on schooling and I
would I would on both of those days when
I'm working at the at the lumber mill I
worked graveyard and then on the
weekends I also worked of course night
times so I didn't go to bed till 4:00 or
5:00 in the morning
DJing clubs don't get out till 2:00 2:30
and then you got to pack up and go home
you know so of course it's just burrito
and sleep but so I would I would not
plan my sleep very accordingly often and
I would only sleep a few hours and then
instead of trying to get a nap in here
to film or myself as I would just
consume more caffeine and then I would
separate that from what I was getting
crippling [__] anxiety all the time
and it wasn't just caffeine but the
caffeine is definitely enough to punch
you right in the dick and say but you
stressed out about this thing right now
and feel it in your heart and then you
start thinking about your heart beating
too fast and that makes your heart beat
faster yeah we've been there huh
caffeine caffeine and take how much are
you consuming it they all have
milligrams soda has caffeine energy
drinks have caffeine your coffee has
caffeine how much are you consuming all
these extra shots like sure you're
feeling sure you're feeling great but
that you're gonna have a crash how much
better are you gonna feel if you just
get some better sleep right and that's
something that's a huge thing too right
that's that's something that I care
about now more than I used to is sleep I
used to not give a crap about sleep I
prided myself on sleeping four and a
half to five hours a night
but it's like I died so you're not
healing your muscles need need sleep to
heal your brain needs sleep to heal like
think about studying for a test how
exhausted you feel afterwards consuming
things with your brain consuming content
makes you exhausted you need extra sleep
from that sleep is something I won't go
too far into it's so important though I
think the biggest thing that I want to
mention here just because this is where
I was I used to tweet Mackinaw use
Twitter a lot I would tweet that I hated
naps I thought now it was my personality
a part of Jake Rhines his personality
was OJ cake snaps he makes fun of him he
thinks there's no time for naps like I
had that as part of my personality and
I'm not saying there's there's nothing
wrong with that like you don't you don't
have to love naps but it kept alive the
fact that like I can fully function on
no sleep and then it projects your
everyday actions into fulfilling who you
think your identity to be right what we
think we are going to enact we're gonna
do we're going to like if I was if I was
sitting there dozing off and I could
probably have a couple hours oh I got a
play gig later I should probably sleep
now because I don't want to nod off as
I'm driving home at 4 o'clock in the
morning on the freeway for an hour
because you get tired when you're up
late obviously right well I could have
taken a nap earlier but my personality
says I hate knit me I'm cool naps are
for sissies well I'm glad I changed that
and now I don't think naps are for
sissies I think naps are for smart
people who need naps right if you need a
nap take a nap take care of your sleep
you know the amount of time that we stay
up late just jamming jamming jamming and
not working at full capacity just just
check when you're tired and say what
capacity I meant am i working out like
40% right now in my 32 percent and then
if I just slept for a few hours or I
just went tomato and now and maybe woke
up earlier with some discipline if I
woke up earlier would I feel like I'm
working on this paper at 70% because you
know what where's the in-between for you
here ask yourself where you're gonna do
your best work don't be afraid to sleep
sleep is good it's how you recover we
need sleep
we got a recharge
earning your morning generally I guess
that's kind of a jump around again but
earning your morning is really an
important thing just whether you got
good sleep or not just really taking
control every morning like taking stock
of how you feel and then if you don't
feel that great saying all right here's
how I feel
here's how I'm going from that like work
from where you're really at take stock
of where you're at in the morning when
you're morning if you wake up with
someone if someone who wakes up with
depression me sometimes I wake up and
I'm just like dude it's not a good day
I'm feeling rough I don't know if it's
things that I'm you know the last couple
years I have it has improved but I do
still have my days you know once twice a
month sometimes farther in between if I
haven't been like super on on my diet I
noticed I'll wake up and it's like I
mean I could look over a Shay and just
say oh it's not mm-hmm it's not one of
those days
but what I do instead of self while I
mean saying I'm here and I'm feeling
this and I need to be taken care of
and it's the saddest day ever and I'm
gonna wallow in this and I'm just gonna
really think about why I feel like this
and I'm gonna loop it and I'm gonna stay
in this loop all day
I say well I've got a farther finish
I've got a farther start line I'm just
farther back I've got to work harder to
get where I need to be maybe I'm not
gonna be in the best mood maybe I'm not
gonna be able to get to like the super
happy exuberant obtuse sharp great ready
to rock Jake but I'm not gonna let it
defeat me I've got a life to live I've
got [__] to do I'm I'm gonna say no to
this depression so wake up if you can if
you have the strength to say I'm gonna
try and it's not about getting to be
perfect it's not about getting to be
alright I feel the happiest I've ever
felt I feel such equanimity now I can
get to work that's not what it's about
maybe you're searching for that year
you're leaning towards that that would
be great that's what you're comparing
your current thought to right but you
need to just grab control of it you'd be
surprised you'd be amazed you'd be blown
away at how much strength you're given
by just grabbing hold of your mourning
by that I mean all right I'm having a
bad day for me I wake up and like this
it's a depress O'Day
it's Jake that a press guide today
that's who he is and then I get out of
bed and I put one foot on the ground and
even if I'm feeling shitty from feeling
groggy from feeling sore my body sore my
brain hurts I just had a bunch of
nightmares probably so I'm just like not
thinking about the right things I put my
foot on the ground I jokingly say let's
get dis bread and I do I eat I do a
little dab if you're watching this on
video I put my fist with the palm facing
upwards and then I
180 that [__] flip it over and I say eat
and it's goofy and it's dumb and it's
not a magic thing but what did I say you
give things power and that gives me
power I've done it enough times I've
added it like try not to like kind of
laugh at yourself you know try not to
break out of it a thought or a that
becomes a mood becomes a personality
right so the thought waking up in the
morning I'm not feeling great well am I
going to continue to feed this thought
am I gonna continue to ask my brain and
justify why I'm feeling this thought am
I gonna say here's why here's why I'm
thinking the way that I am and of course
I am because I suck in and of course I'm
this and I'm justifying this and I'm
reaching back into my past and finding
reasons why I'm feeling this way and I'm
you know I'm really just trying to find
comfort in in safety of why I should not
change my current mood and why I should
not try to adjust where I'm at
well no no I'm feeling this way all
right cool accepted it done I'm feeling
this way I'm gonna have to work a lot
harder than I thought I was gonna have
to work today just to get there that's
okay
let's get this bread so what I do is I
put on my biggest thing in the morning
and I do this even when I'm not feeling
sad I do this actually fairly often like
I said don't go check it on your phone
don't go browsing through your phone
don't worry - emails don't read your
text but hold up YouTube and just search
morning motivation and just you know
take a quick finger don't go obsess and
don't go looking through too much [__]
right don't let your phone pull you in
but just click on one and see if it javi
I listen to it but headphones in I like
as I'm getting ready in the morning so
I'll put headphones in as I'm letting
the dog outside a lot of headphones in
and it's just you know a lot of it's
kind of cheesy right a lot of it's kind
of this like you don't don't
fear say no affair like it's a lot of
like intense stuff sometimes but a lot
of it's a lot of a psychological like
just kind of giving you advice of how to
conquer your mind there's so many
different compilations of just
motivational videos and look if you're
someone who doesn't identify that should
don't work for me that's corny
I don't like that [__] well do you like
being sad because here's something that
works change what change change what
you're doing change what you're trying
if if you wake up and your brain is
trying to get you or or the food you ate
your diet the things you drink you wake
up a little hangover whatever it is if
if your brain is trying to get you in
the morning it's trying to say let's be
self-loathing
let's just go sit on the couch let's
start our morning with that let's let's
let's not reach for our goals let's feel
this sadness and let's ruminate say no
you know there's tons of things you can
do but really I suggest this one to a
lot of people a lot of different types
of people like people who aren't
athletic people who aren't intense
people who are really chill I still
suggest them listen to that [__] like
Tony Robbins yelling in your ear in the
morning and giving you advice it's
putting different thoughts in your head
than you had and it makes you go he's
got a point he's got it Bubba and then
before you know it it's been an hour and
you're kind of like you got momentum on
your other things well if you don't want
to do that if motivation isn't your
thing wake up and stretch or if you wake
up and you're Phil in the press and you
feel super sad get active move do 10
minutes of cardio go to your backyard
and sprint go literally put some shoes
on put some headphones on and sprint to
the end of your block and sprint back
and say do I feel ready don't feel like
I push that [__] out yet
no all right sprint again and if your
neighbors look at you wave at him and
say morning guys I've got depression it
[__] with me I'm getting rid of it
though they're gonna say no okay nope
whatever do your thing man I wasn't
judging you I'm just I wish I had the
off to do that do what you got to do
take care of yourself who cares what
other people are talking about who cares
about going to the gym you do you know
well you should care about going to Jeff
but in that moment in the morning when
your morning seriously when you're
morning get in control of your thoughts
tell yourself what you're gonna do
riding riding helps a ton if you can if
you can establish a riding plan in the
morning even if it's just jotting down a
few things get a few thoughts set a
standard of I write half a page a day
and then doesn't have to be bullet
doesn't have to be paragraphs it could
be bullet points you could literally
write I mean dude spaced it out you're
like right seven bullet points and you
got pretty much half a page right there
that's enough if you've got more the
next day if you can write like a whole
page of like hey this thing's been
bothering me but now that I'm looking at
it on paper I'm glad I'm working through
it like right without you we think that
we need to follow like a journal prompt
we think that we need to write something
social media has changed the way that we
type in the way that we word things that
were saying we think that we word things
in a sense of everybody else reading
them if everybody else consuming them
how is it understandable to everybody
else but when it's just you and your
piece of paper when it's just you and
your notebook when it's just you and
your I encourage physical writing you
can write you know in your notes and
your phone or on the laptop that's fine
but I encourage physical writing I think
it gets it down it makes you slow down a
bit more but it changes it changes you
man it's so important again you can
watch crazy amounts of videos on the
importance of writing and how it changes
your brain and you can look at reviews
all over read it I just read one last
night that this guy was talking about
like I've been writing every single day
for the last year and it's changed my
life in ways that I couldn't imagine
here's how and he wrote like this long
just beautiful personal sharing and it
seems like his words were super
articulate and he talked about how he
didn't realize what he was thinking
about until he wrote it down so maybe
even the morning just wake up you fill
in shitty write down what's going on and
don't it doesn't really proper you don't
the spell [__] right doesn't be good
handwriting doesn't be with the right
marker doesn't have to be in the right
place just write it down get it out
figure out what you're thinking about
you don't know what you're thinking
until you think right now what are you
gonna say next
what are you gonna think next you don't
know sometimes we don't know what the
hell's going on until we write it down
so in the mornings get physical
stretch don't check your phone try
fasting coffee no creamer get rid of the
creamer your physical and right try
something different when you're morning
it's this typical
to preneur like master the morning thing
but anybody at all wake up 20 minutes
earlier oh and here's another thing
snooze button snooze alarms if you're a
snoozer listen up whatever you're doing
if you listener right now if you're
snoozer i'm going to take two seconds
snoozers if you hit snooze in the
morning listen to me you know that you
know his news think about this next time
you wake up in the morning and you go to
hit snooze just say no or hits or hit
stop and just get up out of bed
it's the seconds right after you turn
the alarm off I used to be a snoozer
forever like I said I worked I worked
graveyard I literally went to work at
4:30 p.m. and then I got home at like
5:00 a.m. or something so you know I
wouldn't wake up till 11:30 so every day
I'd be woken up by alarm because you
don't like missed the day of course so
wake up from an alarm and out hit snooze
and I would lay in bed for it be this
like hour of like kind of towards it I'd
be checking on my phone and checking
social media and trying to comment back
and stuff but mostly I was kind of just
nodding in and out of like waking up and
hitting snooze like you fall asleep for
four minutes and then your hands on your
thing that stuff sucks don't do that you
got this
do not hit snooze anymore if you're a
snoozer stop I just don't think it's
good it's terrible actually it feeds the
wrong beast as far as I'm concerned I
actually you know I'll say maybe I was
lucky maybe and something just clicked
for me and I hope he can click for you
but one day I actually just decided I'm
not gonna hit snooze or I decided before
bed and I was feeling particularly
exuberant about it obtuse about it I
felt confident in it and I just the next
morning I woke up and I like I'm I'm
sure my alarm went off but I either way
I didn't hit snooze I just got out of
bed like once your feet are on the floor
yeah it's gonna be colder than in inside
the bed yeah it's not as comfortable
yeah you want a few more minutes but we
have these personality traits of like
five more minutes come on five more
minutes that's like this typical thing
we've saw we saw in movies and like we
saw it as we are watching all these
cartoons growing up and it's really
harming us when you're morning stop
hitting snooze here's one more good
thing about this news
you could try Mel Robbins who is a
motivational speaker type lady person
and she has this five-second rule and
it's so simple but it works and you
could train yourself to use it and
you'll be using it in the background of
your subconscious mind without he
realize it once you train yourself five
seconds so you wake up and you're an
asset count down no options it's not a
[__] option in five seconds I'm out
this bet five seconds so you wake up Oh
alarm goes off and you hit snooze and
you five four three two one and your
feet are on the ground at one give
yourself five seconds and don't get past
that five seconds this you can use this
the five-second rule it's actually it's
so simple it's so overly obvious right
try it and what you do is you make it a
habit or just a sack of habits guys you
make this five-second rule a habit in
the morning and it gets you out of bed
if you hit snooze and you don't want to
be hitting snooze anymore you don't have
to it's part of your personality now
you've been doing it for a long time but
it's because we're we're a victim to a
lot of this a lot of what we think is
normal and in what when our phones are
doing to us right
don't hit snooze you don't have to I
have an instan use for freaking ever I
actually wake up without an alarm a lot
of the times now - but snooze if you
snooze you lose
stop losing when you're morning
caffeine breath work I talked about
breath work there's a ton when it comes
to breath work but I really just think
start the journey right there's a lot
there's a lot of info there a lot of
it's weird I understand if you don't
want to go outside and do like the weird
wim HOF breathing and your neighbors are
gonna think you're crazy for one screw
your neighbors and you could probably
teach him a thing or two right you
should be able to take care of your own
body without being made fun of right
yeah you should but I get that it feels
weird but that man for me going outside
like especially the morning going
outside and taking into big little
breaths it really it really calms you
down there's a lot of work around that
so the very least just become aware of
your breath
and how am i breathing where's my
physiology and right with breath you can
look at posture right in the mornings
postures and other things you cannot you
can add in the morning um all these
things are irrelevant for non morning
activities too by the way at any time of
the day where's my breath is it in my
belly where it focus on it you could
change it you can you can sharpen it I
did a bunch of singing lessons and I
started to notice that my breath not
only went lower and it was sitting in
different eras my body but it was kind
of more of a 360-degree breath so we
have you know if you put your hands on
your on your on your obliques let's say
index finger so we're gonna go like this
we're gonna do like little pinchers all
for our fingers together little pinchers
we're gonna put it on our low ribs right
there and we can fill our four fingers
on either side is in like the the fleshy
fun part I've run underneath our ribs
there a little belly here and then if
you'd fill your thumbs back there your
thumbs back there so you can actually
feel expansion back there not sure
exactly how big our lungs technically
are I mean they're they're pretty big I
think they're they're up higher than
anything but you can feel expansion in
your organs or whatever it is back there
from a belly breath and I was able to
feel that more after I did a lot of
singing exercises a lot of like um
chanting a lot of breath work those sort
of things and it wasn't something I
purposely you know meant to do is like
let's see if I can get my 360 degree
breath it's just after a while you kind
of change your your stagnant state you
change your your homeostasis to have a
breath in a different area of your body
so breath work just you can feel where
is where it is physically with your
hands or not just be aware of where your
breaths up it's not wrong wherever your
breath is if it's shallow that's okay if
it's if it's deep that's okay too but
just just kind of note where it's at
throughout the day especially in the
morning and you can adjust it um I've
got a lot more to do here but I
committed to making this making this
video so let's keep going
pornography let's talk about pornography
I don't watch pornography I no longer
masturbate to porn I actually try as
often as I can to not masturbate because
I think that as far as what I want to
accomplish in life I don't think that
having those thoughts are more important
than the things that I want to do so you
can train yourself and you could realize
how often you've been thinking that I
follow a couple sites or I follow a
couple subreddits with thousands and
thousands of people there's like porn
free and no FAP and I've done a lot of
research on it and I've listened to a
lot of people's personal like hey here's
why I stopped beating off and here's why
and here's how it affected me guys
[__] kangaskhan Genghis Khan however
you say his name dude he is the only
person who in biological times was able
to see like as many naked women as were
able to see as many naked men as we're
able to see if you're a woman I don't
think that it's good for us to be
consuming all this porn it makes us look
at at each other as pieces of me I don't
think that it's good to be seeing all
your friends on Instagram in in like
bathing suits and all their sexiest
their sexiest outfits all the time I
think that it it just sitting there
consuming these things hour an hour and
having thoughts that we're not aware of
I don't think that it's healthy for us
it's not healthy for us it's not good
for us I think that it's something that
could be addressed it seems weird to
talk about nofap to talk about
masturbation right like why would you
tell me why would you tell me about that
I'm not trying to give you some like
you're gonna go to hell if you beat off
I mean do your thing man we all got
urges but I do want to tell you that if
you don't feed the beast if you just
start noticing when you're having these
thoughts start noticing when you're
being a horndog start noticing when
you're when you're letting your thoughts
be consumed on it go like I got some
time I'll see if I can squeeze in you
know a little little beat-off sash no
man you start noticing that when it's
like do I want to do that do it it's
just like the mouth pleasure thing do I
want to do I want this few minutes of
pleasure is that more important than
what I really want to do with my day
when I really want to do with my life it
makes you see people I think that we all
you know something we can't talk about
right it's something that's super weird
but they
is a sense of like guy or girl of like
this like really biological part of us
that's like way in the back of like this
like this weird uncomfortable like yes
would have sex or no would not have sex
with like this like grunting ate part of
our brain right that is always on and
now it's on so much and these
[__] sell you whatever they
want with what they know will work so
people who are just addicted to porn now
and people who are just watching
consuming so much porn who are just you
know slaves to their to their lower
conscious urges man I've been there I've
totally been there but I I just want to
I want to talk about it because my life
is a lot better now by not consuming
those things by not like I don't [__]
with porn I don't watch it it's wrong to
me and the farther distance that I've
had from it is actually made me feel
like a like a Christian dad about it or
something I'm like I'm like no dude it's
it's evil I'm like I'm wondering like
the titles man like porn
okay let's really take a look at that
the titles of things that's weird like
stepson bangs stepmom when he's not like
the weird things that they're planting
in our head I mean this affects you know
the way that we see the world it affects
our small urges and I think that if you
really want to win if you want to win
and be your higher conscious being if
you want to be your the best version of
you if you want to feed the good wolf
not that dark wolf you're just one
little thing that you can do that will
really start shaping that like telling
that wolf nah bro you don't control me
you know I'm not just gonna act on my
urges what are you talking about you can
sharpen that voice that's like get out
wolf and you sharpen that by saying I'm
not gonna masturbate I'm not gonna I'm
not gonna pull up this porn account I'm
gonna I'm not gonna do that I'm not
gonna do it anymore I'm gonna try not to
do it for this amount of time wherever
you're at listen if you're someone who
who looks at porn every day all day
six times a day you just you just jerkin
and wank and man that's you it's all you
man that's your life but it's a
affecting other areas of your life that
you may not be aware of and I want to
point this out because the these
websites are making you a sucker man
they're making you a sucker don't be a
sucker don't don't let these [__]
don't don't let them catapult in in grab
your your monkey mind your reptilian
brain your lower conscious self and
Inlet and let him have have the driver's
seat you know let him make the decisions
don't be doing that you don't have to
these people are trying to get money
they're trying to get you on their sites
and that is the goal and they've gotten
very good at it with social media with
porn all this stuff they're finding ways
to dig into the deepest parts of like
the weirdness of our psyches male/female
wherever you are it's just take a look
at what's going on sure it feels great
but I promise you that if you kind of
just just don't bow down to that beast
and just work a little bit like you get
you had a relapse a big deal starting in
the next day like alright let's see if I
can go five days without this let's see
if I can go ten days without this like
before you know it becomes a thing we're
like oh yeah I mean I haven't
participated in done
I haven't masturbated in months I
haven't masturbate in weeks I haven't oh
poor like I don't really I don't really
watch porn like if if it's your thing
like I get it it's totally fine you know
I'm just trying to offer some some
trying to have those weird conversations
right I just I'm telling you man porn
affects you in weird ways
seeing everybody you know Instagram ads
who you follow on Instagram needs to
follow a bunch of baddies accounts on
Instagram much like tattooed goddesses a
bunch of like tattoo just like hot girls
and then the sake of though it was
literally to see hot girls like to see
and just I never really looked at like
why is it that I want this why do I want
to see this um you know like it's it's
this well of course she's hot there's
that but then you don't really ask
yourself if that thought benefits you if
reacting to that thought benefits you if
consuming this benefits you there's a
great simple thing my friend Erik
teaches his his um he had my friend
teaches a students he says does is this
helpful he just says that sentence and
always sticks with me in the same thing
and you can ask yourself is this helpful
and a segment will helpful for what to
feel good yeah but we're stuck in this
instant gratification mode we're stuck
in this let's just feel good now let's
see what we can do to get as far away
from from uncomfort as we can if you
start feeling boredom uh uh time to beat
it no no ma'am don't let that [__]
catapult you so just take a look at that
sort of thing
masturbation just don't let it control
you that's all you know it's your body
explore your body whenever way you want
to it's your body just don't let them
control your mind through your body
right mental health man mental I've been
kind of talking about the physical like
what we got to do to take care of our
bodies and mental health news media I
mean obviously this is I mentioned like
consuming news in the morning they're
trying to get you on their platforms how
much and this is not just the morning
how much news are you consuming
especially in times of coronavirus right
now when you bless me when the world's
on fire like literally Australia is on
fire it's just really weird to joke
about the world being on fire when
Australia is on the fire but what what
do you consuming what is the news
telling you to think about because when
you look around and you look at your you
get right here in your physical reality
and you say okay who do I interact with
who's in my family that I interact with
who do I know and who are my neighbors
who are my co-workers because when we
when we forget to see people who they
really are and we just consume a lot of
content we start believing people the
people around us and the people in our
lives and the people on the screens are
are what we are told that they are this
as a person who is a left he's on the
left which means okay well I know
everybody left has this list of things
that they likely think so as soon as
you're talking to someone in real life
now you're automatically bringing all of
your preconceived ideas to that
conversation and when you don't realize
that you're treating them as if they are
those things that you pre-conceived
about them you don't give them an open
slate and this is like a huge huge
reason why we can't [__] communicate
in this country in this world right now
because we are treating each other based
off of the avatars that we believe each
other to be we are we we are identifying
with what we believe about each other we
are identifying with what the news media
and what social media has said people
are in that just ain't the truth if
you're noticing your and fear all day
just like I was talking about you know
you can you can bring yourself to a
stressful state you can bring yourself
in bed you can make yourself your body's
equivalent could be I'm about to bungee
jump with your thoughts you can bring
your heart rate up and you're sweating
and you're stressed out just as if
you're about to bungee jump you can do
that to yourself in bed so what do you
think that someone else can do to you
with the news right and they know this
they know this really well it's their
whole entire business plan and listen
you don't even have to consider like
news to be evil you don't have to
consider it to be like a Mark Zuckerberg
where or Jeff Bezos you're evil like a
you know but there's there's six
companies running 90% of our news media
and they're not out for your health so
if you're not looking out for yourself
there's [__] nobody looking out for
yourself you need to look out for you
because if you're consuming all this
content and you're letting it change
your mind and letting it choose what
you're mad about letting yourself argue
argue with people we haven't my it's my
ten year reunion from high school and
there's like crazy amounts of drama and
there's people arguing and there's
people like meeting each other just at
they're wrong opinions not as who they
are as a person the news and social
media the consumption of it are as an
individual if you're listening
your consumption of news and social
media is under your control you've got
it you've got to keep that [__] in check
it's gonna change your mind it when I
took a break from social media
I mean it's Jesus Christ man I realized
how often I was thinking the wrong thing
how often I was spending time arguing
with people this it's just not really
even an argument I'm arguing out the
thought above their head and they're
arguing at the whatever they think I am
I don't feel better about winning I
don't think that anything is actually
solved through social media especially
like Facebook comments reddit comments
there's there's a there there's some
good and reddit comments but when it
when it comes to the news like what
they're telling you what's going on in
the world or what we should be
concentrating on it's not important it's
it's it's it's not important to be
rather checked in 24/7 right it's not
important to be what they say is
important when they say it's important
is not actually what it's important you
need to double-check that because you
get alerts to your phone like Apple news
spotlight like Trump slams the Dems and
it's like 4:00 p.m. like and you're just
like chilling you had a great day and
then now you just from 4:00 to 5:00 p.m.
you're like pissed about Trump slam on
the Dems what like like throughout the
day you have these people have access to
poke your buttons whenever they want if
you have notifications on on your phone
they literally ding hey [__] you and
that's what's happening ding your
believes are stupid ok this person from
across the world said that you suck in
your ugly ding this person doesn't like
you this person thinks they have to be
figured out you should fight them
because they don't know you they don't
know you they don't know me we get mad
we get crazy we get we get out of our
goddamn minds because of this social
media stuff when you need to look the
iPhone came out in 2007 I always
emphasize that I always say that because
when you really think we're in 2020 now
13 years ago
how much has life changed because of
these cell phones because of the content
that we're able to receive constantly on
these cell phones we don't need to be
consuming news constantly watch your
news intake who are you consuming news
from is it biased
they making fun of people is that how
you solve problems lots of stuff right
take a look at it
gain some awareness learning how to
learn learning how to learn is a huge
thing that's something that I've done
figuring out how I learn I've got a th
DS I've got the OC DS self-diagnosed to
whatever I don't know but it's hard to
pay attention right we've all got that I
think especially in the digital world I
think everybody has some sort of like
digital ADHD at this point for me I
would want to be learning things so I'll
put my phone on Do Not Disturb and I'd
put on a YouTube video like or like a
lecture in in when I say YouTube video
it's usually like some some good content
like a like a professor giving a lecture
like teaching something about emotional
like meditation teachers give like an
hour-long talk a lot of the times right
before they teach that meditation
themselves meditation masters like sit
down with each other and have like three
hour long conversations healthy podcast
so a lot of times I will set up my phone
to listen to these things headphones or
not and it's hard to pay attention right
it's like you think of something else so
you get a notification you click on that
and that stops the screen or you think
of something else you should be doing
you don't have this consistent whatever
for me I had to figure out how I learned
it started to realize like oh I don't
learn super well when I'm doing a
million things or when I'm just like
aimlessly wandering around or I'm
letting myself click off of this all the
time so I would set like alright let's
go
hit play headphones in and I would
I've got sometimes a highlighter sitting
next to me I've got a page of notes I've
got and I'm just you know I'm not
getting graded on this I'm not getting
tested I'm not getting I'm not getting
scored for this
I'm not taking notes so my teacher can
check them I'm not taking notes because
I have a test coming up there is no pass
or fail this is how do I want to consume
this content how am i best able to learn
this so sit there with notes and just
jot down some random [__] and just
whatever keeps you focused don't don't
be writing too much because that'll pull
you in and start writing your own
thoughts and if it does like if it's
that's important it send you off on a
spiral pause that thing just don't don't
get distracted but uh another thing that
I do because sometimes note writing
isn't enough for me if I'm a leg
twitching and I'm like looking around
and I'm having trouble just listening or
I'll get distracted by a squirrel
outside so what I do is I use my finger
board
finger board tech deck so you guys
remember tech decks from back in the day
now they have savage ones and they cost
an embarrassing amount of money
sometimes for the for the dress like the
legit ones but they've got like bearings
and they're pressed apply in there
they've got their great the great shape
they're wider but so what I do as I'm
consuming content or I'm listening to a
lecture or I'm let's say studying for
something I've got my pen in my pad I've
got my pen in my piece of paper I'm
writing it down but then my right hand
is just doing little flip tricks I'm
just mindlessly with my right hand
playing with my finger board and I'm not
focusing on the fingerboard like I'm
just trying to do the same kickflip a
million you know ten thousand hours just
try to millions of times that's how you
get good at that stuff I've got my own
private things like so it's basically
like like well I'm sitting there
twitching my leg that's my leg twitch
I'm like deploying my attention to my
hand to finger board and that's how I
learn and so it works for me like joke's
on you teachers all those years that you
took away my tech decks maybe I'm just
being defiant this is like the ultimate
defiance now that I'm 28 I have mastered
tech tacking and learning you can't tell
me [__] teach but another thing that you
could do so whatever your version of
tech decking or fingerboarding is like
if you have like a little spinner if you
have something that you can just sit
there and spin around your finger
something that's not that's kind of a
mindless you don't have to think much
but it kind of deploys parts of your
attention so you can consume this and
then set it down like like I'll use my
right hand and I write with my right
hand so once I think I hear something
profound or I'll or they'll say
something that gives me another thought
or I'm like okay I want to remember that
I'll repeat it out loud to myself talk
to yourself out loud that's another one
repeat it out loud
write it down sit down my fingerboard
write it down really quick set down that
pen and then get back okay keep going if
you got to pause the video you got to
pause the video if you need to
shuffle back on YouTube you shuffle back
so whatever way that you're learning
audiobook you're playing it through a
Lexie you're playing it through
headphones you're reading do what you
got to do to learn something that I
would do
I found myself fairly enable to sit down
and read a book and that's something
that's probably not too shocking to many
people you'll realize that the way that
civilization the way that our society
has changed drastically in the last you
know 13 years or shorter or longer
whatever we have our attention span is
different our attention span is way
different especially young kids growing
up with with cell phones who grew up
with cell phones I mean I was I was in
high school when some when cell phones
were coming out we had the razor I
graduated in 2010 and so we are riding
the wave of Technology you know but now
we're able to look back and say okay how
did this cool amazing cool things that
we had how did they affect us and now
we're able to see like man our
intentions man is super affected by how
often were on this thing it changes
everything about everything so is your
attention span now who cares how you
were back then
right how old are you right now you're
this many years old you're this day old
how's your attention now do you need to
change something do you need to try
something new assess where you're at now
if you need to try something that I
would do is I would oftentimes like get
the same book and audiobook I guess not
often times but I've done it a couple
times I would pace back and forth in
this room random it and to be playing
over my speakers loudly on Alexa and
it's playing the audiobook but in my
hand I have a highlighter and the
physical book and I'm like I'm listening
and I'm reading and then I hear
something and I highlight it if I need
to and I keep pacing back and forth you
can even set a timer and set it for an
hour set it for a half hour ten minutes
a day at 20 minutes a day whatever learn
how you learn my friend
change it up who you who you used to be
before all this crazy-ass technology
changed our brains and tons of ways you
may not learn that way very well anymore
and by learning these things you may be
able to actually learn how other people
learn and help them a little bit better
like if you're if you're a parent you're
gonna want to learn how they learn
differently because they don't learn the
same way that we learned when we were
kids it's just different so try
different things there's no wrong way to
learn just literally say like how am i
consuming this content and what am I
remembering from it you know do what you
got to do like if this if you're if your
brain is still in the morning let's
think if you're if you're learning is
after so you get off work at 5:00 and
you're like alright I got two hours to
learn every night from 5:30 to 7:30 and
then it's family time I wind down and
watch TV I eat whatever 5:30 to 7:30
that's you learn time well set it aside
and plan it and say I'm gonna do this
and then actually talk about how you
talk with yourself or assess at the end
of those two hours like okay what did I
learn give yourself a summary even and
hey also being a dolt
smoke some weed or drink some wine right
like I've got I've got a glass of wine
on my once a week learning about
mathematics like if that's what gets you
to pay attention that's what makes you
like alright I'm relaxed you know we
accompany like like weed in alcohol
again you know watch a watch a
consumption of all these but we add it
to to like a social setting only or it's
only about getting [__] up or it's
because I had a rough day
we are why behind a lot of these things
is controlled by other people's ideas a
lot of the times right so what works for
you having a glass of whiskey having a
glass of wine treating yourself to to
your favorite IPA every Tuesday night so
you can get three hours of learning in
set some time to yourself we we've got
to learn we've got to be learning no
matter how old you are I think that in
our society we have
a cultural blind-spot of learning we
think that we stop learning after school
like once nobody's teaching you we
[__] throw up our papers in the air
and say I'm never learning again and
we're proud of that
that sucks don't be proud of not
learning find a way to learn and listen
you're always learning you're learning
at all times you're learning 24/7
whatever you're consuming these people
are telling you what to think what are
you thinking about they're giving you
things to think about you're thinking
about them so you're always teaching
yourself what you know right you're
always everything that you're consuming
everything that you're doing everything
that's in front of you you're consuming
it you're reading it you're you're
eating it with your mind and then what
what are you doing with it how is it
affecting your life like if you're only
learning about what the Kardashians are
doing for eight hours a day
that's your hobby like your hobby is is
filling your mind with Kardashian
information I mean if you write a
Kardashian a blog post and you run a
weekly blog like maybe that's your work
that's great but whatever you're
constantly consuming is what you're
doing is what you're learning about so
don't let other people tell you what to
learn about don't let other people put
this [__] on you don't let other people
don't let people who are just trying to
make money by keeping you on their
content pages tell you what to learn if
it's not benefiting your life learn how
you learn try your ways do different
ways go outside go in public I don't
like being in public I get distracted
when I'm learning I don't like having
loud noises I can't work with headphones
on AB my good buddy Kelly he works great
he goes he would go to Starbucks before
the quarantine and he would sit in there
with headphones in and he would crank
out so much complex math homework and it
was always so impressive to me I was
like dude I don't know how you do that
how do you not get distracted but he's a
social guy he likes you know what take
his headphones off bumping into people
he's able to get right back to work he
kills it in an aspect but I know me
because I've learned how I've learned I
don't work well under those
circumstances I work well when I'm by
myself and I have things set up with how
I need them set up I've learned through
trial and error how I learn best I need
some peace sometimes what puts
murdered noises on the computer that's
just delightful I don't want to hear
people talking though it throws me off
so I've learned how I learned learn how
you learn
dopamine detox you can look those up
online dopamine detox like a ton of
people have because a lot of
entrepreneurs instead of talking about
this but essentially try to go like a
day or ten days or 30 days without the
things that you love right like try to
do no phone for a whole day we're trying
to do no caffeine for a week or or would
just detox yourself you know dopamine
that's why we're on these things that's
why we love notifications it's the same
it's the same thing this is how easy we
are you know as much as we love like
when we pull the lever at a at a casino
we love seeing if we won it's a slot
machine this is a slot machine we get
that dopamine like like uh-huh are they
gonna line up like when you've seen
those things spinning when that happens
we get that dopamine detox of course
we're pumped about the money but also
the visual effects they've got that down
we they know exactly what to put up
there the flashy colors everything to
get us to get excited about that we
release his dopamine they're doing the
same thing on our phones and when I say
they it sounds like I'm talking about
some evil overlord there might be who
knows but I'm just saying people other
than you I'm not trying to say that
there's like a bunch of evil out to get
you maybe there is I don't [__] know
seems like it's sometimes right but I'm
just reminding you to take control of of
all these great things that we have that
we consume them but they're not they
consume us right if we ain't careful you
consume us so don't let this this slot
machine control your life
[Music]
music what are you consuming what are
you consuming throughout the day the
lyrics mm-hmm I mean they might have
effects on you if you play Grand Theft
Auto 5 every single day from ages 3 to 7
you're gonna your brain is gonna be
thinking differently I'm not going to
say I'm not saying you're gonna go out
like a murder a bunch of people just
cause you played on the videogame but
what you consume changes you so I mean
it seems apparent that the music you
would consume
Changez you too this is a hard one for
me as a DJ I found myself the last
couple years less in connection with
what's hot less I don't know what's on
the top charts I don't know yeah I don't
I don't listen to what's what's being
said right now I'm not watching who's
beefing with who
I'm not following like the Twitter beef
and the EDM beef about who ripped off
who or and in I feel less connected
because of that but I also feel less
connected because listening to the
lyrics
they just don't here's something this
might be a stretch you don't have to
believe this but I like to think of you
know what's a curse what's a back in the
day we heard about curses right like
witches and curses and evil and the
demons and what is a curse right it's
like somebody can make you feel
something or experience something that
you don't want to experience because
they said certain things with their
mouth I think about the power that for
example let's say cardi B I like it when
that song first came out every girl not
I could go a lot of girls like new like
Shea she knew every lyric like it it
changed
she started memorizing it right and
there's nothing wrong with it it's it's
a it's a fun song had we had a great
time and I do just wonder you know get
woowoo with me for a sec I wonder if
these words do have power think about
when you say certain words they put you
in certain moods they when you gossip
about somebody else when you talk about
somebody else when you [__] about
somebody else like and you're like oh
they're this and they're this and you're
saying stuff you're actually feeling
those feelings as you're saying it right
like you're or you're pointing them out
I think I think that as much as words
are simply you know the tool
that we have as humans to describe
feelings but they are powerful it's
incredibly complex there is certain
words not sure exactly but I think
certain cuss words are actually
technically derived from different parts
of our brain or something and I'll have
to double-check on on that fact there
but I don't know I maybe just just think
about what you're consuming it's putting
you in different moods you of course
know that songs and the lyrics can put
you in different moods they can connect
you with certain things I had a friend
who we were we used to like listen to a
ton of like suicide boys and in puia and
shake well and you know I still I still
love that [__] like there's still
certain times where it just hypes me but
I started like kind of noticing more of
like the lyrical content like what are
they saying
and then my friend and I were talking
about liked it just seems it's like
childish what they're saying and I think
I pointed out I emphasized this music
thing it seems like a seems like an
overly obvious seems like a like a
something we already know seems like
something like dude it's just making you
feel better it's making you dance like
if it gets you hyped up it's getting you
there you find but it's also changing
the way you think about things like
think about our language and how pop
culture changes our language think about
like five years ago if you said daddy or
daddy it was a totally different [__]
word no like now it's like if you say
daddy it's uncomfortable because it's
like this sexual porn thing because
that's what music has made it our words
are changed through our culture our
conversations adapt through our media
and especially music I'm not trying to
get all like the devil's in the music
you know get away from it you know but
just be wary of what you're consuming
and what the people are saying and what
moods it's getting you in for me
I used to listen to there's this comfort
if you ever dealt with depression
there's a comfort in feeling sadness
there's a comfort and feeling it's a
weird thing right it's like a I hate
feeling like this but at least it's
familiar right at least it's at least it
feels like I deserve it right it matches
up with what I think about myself so I'm
gonna get myself there meaning you
listen to to dark music you listen to
sad music that gets you thinking certain
thoughts you listen to to music that
brings up certain scenarios and brings
up certain parts of you sometimes that's
good so you can bring up those emotions
and process them like sometimes it's
time to get a cry out right
sometimes it's time to get to process
through this to push through it but it
can become a strange addiction in a way
it become to feel that sadness to make
yourself relive that emotion it can
become a an uncomfortable comfort of
sorts so notice how often your mind is
trying to get you there like oh let's
listen to that song that makes you cry
is it making you cry before you go home
before you go see your family is it
putting you in kind of a different sort
of mood is it is it locking you into
like the childhood trauma side of
yourself and by that I mean like
sometimes I'll get so caught up and like
thinking something and I'm like oh man
that's not actually what I want to think
now as a grown man that's just what I
thought about that thing when I first
learned about it like that's what my 15
year old self would say but I haven't
reassessed that I haven't looked at that
I haven't haven't redone that thought
sometimes music can get us there I used
to I used to when I was driving home
after work like it was always hard it
was always hard to like listen to upbeat
like party music after you've just been
playing for four hours at a club or a
bar and so I would listen to like really
sad music but I would notice like man by
the time I like cry like six times on
the freeway just like because you find
the right songs and it became this
comfort it was part of it that's good
right
there's part
that's you got to drain that [__] listen
to sad music if you have some time to
designate but like right before I'm
trying to go home and wind down and get
better and my thoughts and kind of like
like recharge my batteries you know like
like let my ears kind of like slow let
my thoughts not be so so obsessed with
trying to like mix music and trying to
like think so intricately and calm down
and of course go to bed like you don't
want to be as sad as you possibly can
and cry yourself to sleep there's a
comfort in that right if you've ever
cried yourself to sleep there is a
comfort in it but notice how you got
there notice how you're pushing yourself
there because there's this part in your
brain that's like oh yeah let's feel
that let's put on that sad song again
let's get sad we like that at least
we're now at least we know it's coming
at least being sad is predictable don't
do that to yourself
watch what you're consuming music was
just this videos getting up here in time
about it I wanted to cover everything um
alone time do you designate a long time
do you have a long time real alone time
whether you're an introvert and
extrovert you need alone time and the
reason why is because we're always doing
something because somebody else is
watching or when I was doing something
think about how like a kid all of a
sudden acts different or like a young
teenager you pull out a phone and it's
like a like they walk down a stage and
like they turned on this thing we have
that too right when we're always around
someone you'll notice that your social
self and your you're introverted by
yourself self is a lot of times
different for me I didn't give myself
enough alone time when I was incredibly
depressed I was just just hated being at
home alone because I would just think
bad thoughts and I would not like myself
I didn't like hanging out with myself
and so I would just all right well hit
up more friends and hang out and just
try not to feel that feeling and let's
have some drinks and let's party and
let's feel good and whatever but if
you're not able to hang out with
yourself and have a good time maybe
that's something you can work on being
alone is the I'm gonna emphasize this
being alone
hanging out by yourself it's so
important but I think it's so important
because I want to tell you when you're
alone and you ain't getting weird
then you're doing alone wrong if you're
not a weirdo when you're alone then
you're doing it wrong
do you dance around by yourself what
about putting your favorite song on and
dancing to that every morning all right
before bed what about when you feel
yourself sad you feel yourself being
mopey you go by yourself and you put on
a song that you like and you force
yourself to dance force yourself
nobody's coming to save you nobody else
is gonna do it but you know damn well
four minutes in 38 seconds later you're
gonna feel a lot better even if it's a
reluctant lot better or you're like all
right god damn it okay I guess I am
feeling kind of better my body to get
moving around a little bit you don't to
be good at dancing you don't have to
know dance moves just move your body
when you're alone be weird how else can
you be weird when you're alone stretch
again stretch at all times I mean if you
got five minutes alone take that time to
stretch and move around and move your
eyes and move your neck think about
we're always looking kind of our eyes
are kind of down and to the right in our
right arm is flex more than our like if
you're right-handed its flex more
because your phone you're always kind of
glancing down at your screen in some
sort of way well think about how often
you're doing the exact opposite like
where there's more weight in your left
hand in your glancing kind of up into
the right or up and to the left are our
visual perception is good so imagine
awareness you can you can look at
something and focus on it how do you do
that you your awareness comes to this
thing like if you're looking at the
video you look at me I'm the object and
you kind of float out the background
because you're you're telling yourself
I'm paying attention to this and paying
attention to this person talking in the
background kind of fades interview well
after a while those those are when
you're doing that with your phone your
constant looking at your screen and
you're fading out the the edges of your
screen just like when you're looking at
a movie theater at some point you're
just looking at the screen
the big old movie screen you're not
seeing the the people walk you're not
seeing the people in front of you you
just kind of focus it out again we're
we're biological creatures who didn't
get this way over a long period that you
know what we did but we didn't get to
this societal level of Technology until
more recently like there's there's a lot
that we need to negate and act against
that we do too much so if you're looking
at your phone too much which everybody
is your neck muscles need to be
stretched your eye muscles need to be
stretched your peripheral vision like
how far you're looking at things get out
in nature leave your phone at home if
you can or leave it in your pocket for
an hour what in the car in your bag
whatever and just stretch your eyes and
stretch your face when you're outside
and really look out and notice your
peripherals you know as you're driving
you can do this as you're driving be
safe of course be conscious of trying to
adjust any sort of forms of awareness as
you're driving with with purpose but as
you're sitting back you know you're
looking at just the lane in front of you
you're driving right you're you're
looking out the front windshield you're
focusing on your lane if anybody comes
and tries to do any of the maneuvers
that might get in your way you're gonna
watch those but you're not particularly
like turn your head left and right
you're not particularly like looking
around and everything you're kind of
just zone and out right you're driving
you're at that 95 percent subconscious
part of your brain you know how to drive
if you just let it happen
well what I like to do often is I like
to sit back and kind of like straighten
out my neck and try to you know realize
if my head's kind of tilt tilted leaning
forward and I like to try to just you
know as you lightly have your hands on
your steering wheel try to just look try
to try to see everything that's in your
vision try to not concentrate on
anything because you'll notice I mean
right now you your nose your nose is in
your vision constantly but you've owned
it out look cross-eyed right now
wherever you are look at your nose
that's in your vision at all times but
we're so used to it
right we're so aware of it that it's a
normal thing we don't think about it we
just see through our vision so
alright get used to these things we have
a lot of micro muscles in our neck that
in in everywhere throughout our body
likely that that are related and
connected to these things and I think
that we're gonna look back in years and
years and realize how these little
things affected us more than we thought
so
use your peripherals stretch out your
eyes look at something in its hole stop
trying to zoom in like a hawk and try to
notice one thing like try to point out
different objects look at everything as
a broad just relax your eyes and let it
happen so you can do that as you're
driving you can go out a nature hike
we've got alone time did I cover alone
time
thoroughly yoga let's say you know I say
stretching and stuff to yoga when it
comes to alone time dude you don't have
to be good at yoga to do yoga you don't
have to even say I'm doing yoga just
you've seen the moves before maybe
you've done a couple classes maybe you
haven't you can go online and watch a
couple classes dude just get on the
floor and stretch nobody's around you
can act like a weirdo
add some hum add some / F work at some
ohm add some weirdness so think about it
you know we think there's like magic
powers between like the ohms and the
chants and shoot maybe there is but I
know that oh oh oh oh like those
different levels of using your vocal
cords using your body here we're all
allowed to use it it's our body don't
feel weird for for singing or humming or
whatever don't let people say that you
need to be good or bad at something to
use your own freaking body right well
there correlate two different areas of
our bodies you can talk about you know
people correlate them to the different
chakra areas but if you don't believe in
chakras or if you don't if you don't
know about chakras rather just feel go
hmm-hmm as deep as you can as high as
you can and feel kind of in your body
where that's at and I just encourage you
to do these things when you're alone as
you're stretching just hum feel where
it's at try to concentrate on it as
you're working out and whatever form
that you do
start start humming it's just it sends
energy to different areas of your body
and allows your brain to concentrate on
different areas of your body and kind of
kind of engage different areas like I I
like doing it when I'm actually working
out a lot like I'll be doing a bicep
curl out in the garage with the
dumbbells you know and I'll add in like
a whole hole and it'll actually improve
my posture and then I'll realize I'm
getting a little bit better workout
suddenly because now my core is actually
engaged in areas that it wasn't just a
moment before so chanting be aware of
what music you're consuming seriously
affects you learning learning philosophy
is a huge thing that I want to suggest I
know it seems not super desirable like
you're just gonna go take a philosophy
class but there's a there's a couple
things on YouTube like after school and
philosophize this
I'm always suggesting YouTube but
seriously just you can listen to a few
of these things even the motivational
videos that I was talking about earlier
you listen to these things and they
change your perceptions like you you
don't know what you don't know and a lot
of us are so full of our damn selfs that
we think we know so much [__] you don't
know [__] I don't know [__] even all
this stuff that I'm telling you I don't
know [__] I still don't know [__] so I
still consume every day so I still
consume new content so I can see if I
can challenge my beliefs and learn
something new and have some aha moments
and have some oh okay here's how I could
see the world differently here's how I
can look at that situation differently
here's what I can do differently learn
philosophy I'm not even gonna suggest
like who to learn I think I started well
I guess well I could I guess I started
Jordan Peterson was somebody that I
started with he's a professor he was in
Toronto it's just probably a ton of
information you you can learn about him
but he started like he would tell these
stories in you know talk about like
psychologists from the past and teach me
about Carl Jung and you know teach him
teach me about Freud and as you start to
realize that my you know I started to
realize that my view of reality is not
like the reality like
there's so many different ways of
looking at it and it starts opening up
new pathways for you to think
differently so if you're trapping
yourself if you're if you're if you're
not if you're not able to come to the
correct conclusions and you're not happy
and you're not loving your life and
you're not filled with a self-love if
you have a lot of doubt and you have a
lot of maybe your way of thinking just
isn't working out for you right and you
could challenge your way of thinking and
you could think of new ways to think by
consuming new content you can't do it
all all alone
if you could do it all in your head
cavity you probably would have already
done it right so put more information
into your brain learn more if you want
to learn more there's master class like
we think we have to go to college to
learn we think we have to like our well
I'm gonna go to college next semester
and that's what I'm gonna start learning
now man what about right now go online
go on master class com there's a bunch
of cool stuff you learned so much
different stuff piano philosophy art you
can learn about the Constitution like
there's so many different very like
whatever your interests are there's
places online to learn about it now the
link is do they do like 10 minutes
submarines of books so if you want to
start reading books to learn you can
listen to like a 10 minute summary of
the book to see if it see if a tails you
even a 10 minute summary you can learn a
lot from like a 10 minute summary is
enough to to change your perception of
reality a lot of times the right the
right thing set at the right moment you
know could wake you up in particular
ways so music being reactive content
consuming alone time I covered that
creativity hey if you think you're not a
creative person here at goddamn lawyer
you can be creative you don't have to
compare yourself to how creative other
people are I'm like a creative for a
living so maybe I'm more impressive at
it if you are comparing but that's not
how it works
creativity is just how can you do
something that only you can do right
creative like there's there's almost a
billion people in this world and we can
all create creativity is a human trait
it's not just for creators it's not just
for artists it's not just for writers
it's not just for musicians creativity
is something we can all
do and it's a great outlet it's a great
way out create maybe that's following
along and choosing your own colors on a
coloring book maybe it's trying to draw
something and sucking out drawing you
know
creativity and trying all these things
we we don't allow ourselves to even try
them because we assess where we're at
right now right we say well I'm this or
I'm not a good drawer so I'm not going
to draw I'm not gonna paint so I'm not
gonna paint like what you're not
choosing this as your career path like
maybe you can later cool whatever but
you you can just experience these things
like you want to learn how to play piano
learn how to play piano you don't have
to say I'm a musician I'm gonna be a
musician you can just learn these things
check in your creativity it's gonna help
you find that spot in you that's you
write that spot on you that's you get to
a point in your life right we've all
heard that point like you're like I
don't know what I want to do what's my
purpose what do I want out of life who
do I want to be and we think it's just a
job title we think that's just a I'm
gonna be a nurse I'm going to be a
doctor I'm gonna be a fireman I'm gonna
be a I'm gonna work at the mill I'm
gonna do this and we identify we put our
identity with that right I think that
allowing yourself to to realize that you
are a creator if you're a human being
you are a creator create something it
doesn't have to be to show anybody it
doesn't have to be for anybody create
the it unlocks this this place within
each of us that feels incredibly right
that that tells us you know we've heard
that like that one thing that you've
always kind of wanted to be in the back
of your mind like if you okay if you had
to really if you could do if you had a
magic wand and you could have your dream
career what would it be like there's
like this little voice in your head
that's kind of you from when you were
younger like man I would love to just
own a veterinary clinic art I would love
to produce giant movies one day or I
would love to I always want to make
music videos or Gary Vee talks like I
would love to print blue smoove Smurf
shirts like dude whatever your thing is
follow it or if you don't know what it
is look for it by creating if you're a
human being you allowed to be a creator
I'm gonna summarize all this begin with
the end in mind
start with why I think we've kind of
trained ourselves to do what feels good
what is the most comfortable right now
but what is courage but action through
fear you're gonna feel fear you know we
we get so caught up with our identity
with who we are but where does our
identity live is it within other
people's opinions of you is it in their
minds where is it where is identity if
you if you show up to your family event
on holidays you notice a lot of times
sometimes for some people anyway you
don't click with them or you don't get
along with some people in your family
because they're just treating you like
the 12 year old self the treating you
like your 14 year old version of you
because that's who they remembered that
so they grew up with your family well
who is really you are you that no you're
not that that was a time that that's who
you were at that time but we're this
whole long drawn-out series of events we
have so many years and our identity is
our box our identity is the box we put
ourselves in Who am I
am i allowing myself to be these things
am i these things do other people see me
as these things I think that when you
change your identity when you allow your
identity to change you allow yourself to
not be solved easily or not try to
define yourself as who you are right now
you can just you can relax a lot of
these intricate
things we think we need to do parts of
us that we think we need to be we can we
can relax other people's expectations of
us because what is your identity and who
says what it is I think when you're
willing to shape your identity and
you're willing to revamp yourself and
what you think about yourself and what
you constantly say if you if you add
some awareness into your daily things
you say and things you do you'll you'll
you'll be able to say huh
do I want these things is this what I
want does this match up with what I feel
inside and just like I said earlier you
know you're gonna die one day and that's
not a scary thing that's a beautiful
thing the things not beautiful because
it lasts allow yourself to be the person
that you dream of being allow yourself
to feed yourself the the better parts of
who you want to be don't get sucked into
your habits don't just be a sack of
habits challenge your identity feel what
you're feeling and say what could I be
feeling learn about your feelings don't
let them just affect you and reactive
don't don't be in a reactive State learn
about your mind learn about your body
learn how you learn learn about the
things that you learned that you can
unlearn question your beliefs why am i
doing these things why am I the way that
I am why do I believe this is it because
the people that were raising me when I
was younger taught me these things is it
because the people that I'm around joke
about these things so I like joking
about these things is this a way to fit
in with the people around me listen
people are gonna love you when you're
yourself especially they're gonna love
you the people in your life
they're okay with you changing they're
okay with you setting boundaries and
saying hey I don't want to do that
anymore hey I want to I want to work out
hey I want to hang out buddy but like
you want to go no you want to aren't
gonna run you want to go for a hike you
want to go play frisbee you want to you
want to do something different I want to
be active now because you know your
friends are going to your friends are
gonna be supportive the people who love
you are gonna love you
and in all you got to do is set some
batteries and say I don't wanna I'm not
the person that I used to be I don't
want to identify with those things I
don't want to bow down to those lesser
parts of my you know wolf I don't want
to feed the bad wolf I think at all
times we have at all times we have a
self that we can feed right a dark self
a light self and if you were to start
with why if you begin with the end in
mind of your life and you remember this
isn't permanent impermanence I'm gonna
I'm gonna leave this beautiful earth one
day the people around me they're gonna
leave this earth they've had a whole
life these these people around me they
were children and then they were teens
and now here we are however old you are
and one day you're gonna leave your body
and whenever you do after that
I mean who freaking knows maybe you're
gonna go on but what you do know for
sure is that you have this life now and
taking care of yourself and exploring
and learning about yourself and
challenging yourself and learning what a
self is feed the highest versions of
yourself and
I think we'll leave it at that I
appreciate anybody who's still listening
at this point I would absolutely love to
comment back if you guys have any
questions if you have any like a Q&A I'm
gonna do a QA recording too in the same
sense comment on my on my youtube
wherever you're at take care of yourself
and change the way you think and learn
learn about you man learn how you are
different than other people and see what
works for you and remember that this
life is short but long right you've got
time be patient with yourself don't
worry about the Sinister gratification
don't worry about uncomfort don't worry
about feeling fear you can feel fear all
day but still be courageous through it
you can act through fear you can feel
uncomfortable you can feel different and
and still have action through it
so anybody wherever you're at in your
life if you're at a low point if you're
at a high point if you're listening to
this just cuz you listen to my podcast
if you're listening to this because
somebody sent it to you if you're
listening this because you want to try
to find some little tips and tricks to
get better to make your life more
fulfilling make you make your make your
eyes more capable of seeing beauty of of
noticing when a wonderful sound stops
you in your tracks when when ascent is
that's beautiful you know these five
senses are all we got right or they how
we perceive the world so learn about
them and learn how they make you you and
I didn't mention meditation this whole
time which is I don't know how I managed
to not mention meditation this time but
if you don't meditate if you don't
practice mindfulness please practice
mindfulness this is the first step so
you can become aware of all these things
that has talked about practice
mindfulness you don't have to even sit
down and do it with an app you don't you
have to sit down do it for YouTube video
you don't have to do it for 10 minutes
you have to do for 20 minutes learn
about it
and then whatever that stumbles you into
whatever that brings you in to get on
YouTube min whenever you want to learn
all the stuff that I just talked about
get on YouTube and just search and just
let yourself say I'm here to learn this
isn't work I'm here to enjoy my life
this is good I want to do this I think
this is probably a good idea get on
YouTube everything's free
just learn listen to other people's
ideas of things read some articles
consume content that's good for you take
care of yourself I'm gonna stop rambling
I hope this helped somebody out there
much-loved junkyard love podcast out